<?xml version="1.0"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 
  <title>The Emotional Programmer</title>
  <link href="http://emoprog.com/"/>
  <link type="application/atom+xml" rel="self" href="http://emoprog.com/atom.xml"/>
  <updated>2014-02-06T22:14:03-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://emoprog.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name>Louis Salin</name>
    <email>louis.phil@gmail.com</email>
  </author>

  
  <entry>
    <id>http://emoprog.com/2014/02/06/entry</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://emoprog.com/2014/02/06/entry.html"/>
    <title>February 6, 2014</title>
    <published>2014-02-06T00:00:00-06:00</published>
    <updated>2014-02-06T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Louis Salin</name>
      <uri>http://emoprog.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Sleep: Good. 11:00pm to 8:30am. I did wake up often during the later part of the night.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Breakfast: 2 pieces of bacon&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Lunch: the innards of 3 tacos. This time, it was a mix of potatos, eggs, avocado, spinach, cheese, tomatoes, mushrooms&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Snacks: walnuts and a few cashews. Because the inside of three tacos isn&amp;#8217;t all that much.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Dinner: 2 Italian sausages, green beans, tiny potatoes&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Alcohol: a ounce of Tequila&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rock climbing, you poop me. &lt;br /&gt;
My fingers are jello.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I made some friends at the gym.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://emoprog.com/2014/02/05/entry</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://emoprog.com/2014/02/05/entry.html"/>
    <title>February 5, 2014</title>
    <published>2014-02-05T00:00:00-06:00</published>
    <updated>2014-02-05T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Louis Salin</name>
      <uri>http://emoprog.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Sleep: Good. 11:30pm to 7:30am. Woot! Eight hours! I did force myself to get out of bed. I could&amp;#8217;ve easily fall asleep again for another hour.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Breakfast: 3 eggs, one salmon croquette&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Lunch: 1/4 chicken, veggies&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Snacks: none&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Dinner: chips and queso!&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Alcohol: margarita and a shot of tequila&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I ended my work-everyday experiment, but I may have said that already. I can&amp;#8217;t remember and I&amp;#8217;m too lazy to go back and read my old posts. Anyway, I stopped it not because it was hard to work everyday, but because I felt bad for getting to work after everyone and leaving before anyone else&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started two online classes: Finance, and Model Thinking. I think these two classes go together like goat cheese and crackers. There are people making a killing creating financial models in the real world everyday. I want to make a killing too.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://emoprog.com/2014/02/04/entry</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://emoprog.com/2014/02/04/entry.html"/>
    <title>February 4, 2014</title>
    <published>2014-02-04T00:00:00-06:00</published>
    <updated>2014-02-04T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Louis Salin</name>
      <uri>http://emoprog.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Sleep: Good. 11pm to 8am. I had to force myself not to fall asleep this morning&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Breakfast: ate the inside of three tacos again this morning. It included a bit of mashed potatoes. Did I ever mention I have a v8 every morning at work?&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Lunch: double steak Subway salad with guacamole&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Snacks: walnuts&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Dinner: 2 salmon croquettes (canned wild salmon, one egg, corn meal) fried in olive oil, mustard greens, coconut oil&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Alcohol: a small tequila + lime juice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went rock climbing during lunch and came back hungry. I&amp;#8217;m listening to my body!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My knees are bothering me and I blame rock climbing.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://emoprog.com/2014/02/03/entry</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://emoprog.com/2014/02/03/entry.html"/>
    <title>February 3, 2014</title>
    <published>2014-02-03T00:00:00-06:00</published>
    <updated>2014-02-03T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Louis Salin</name>
      <uri>http://emoprog.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Sleep: Good. 11pm to 9am.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Breakfast: I took three tacos at work, removed the flour tortilla and ate whatever was inside with salsa.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Lunch: none&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Snacks: walnuts&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Dinner: 1/2lb ground beef, mustard greens, a piece of dark chocolate, coconut oil&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Alcohol: none&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://emoprog.com/2014/02/02/entry</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://emoprog.com/2014/02/02/entry.html"/>
    <title>February 2, 2014</title>
    <published>2014-02-02T00:00:00-06:00</published>
    <updated>2014-02-02T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Louis Salin</name>
      <uri>http://emoprog.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Sleep: Ah, finally a good night! I&amp;#8217;m sure being sore had something to do with it. 11pm to 8am.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Breakfast: Scrambled eggs, a bit of refried beans, half a piece of bacon, a small homemade hashbrown.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Lunch: none&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Snacks: none&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Dinner: Double bunless cheeseburger at home, a bit of coconut oil, a plate of cheesy nachos.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Alcohol: a margarita and some whiskey during the super bowl.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My rock climbing performance wasn&amp;#8217;t there yesterday. I struggled on everything I tried and my fingers didn&amp;#8217;t want to hold on to much. Considering I took 2 day breaks in between sessions, I can hardly believe that I need more rest. I need to research this more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I feel bad for eathing those nachos. It was a smallish plate, so I imagine there was about 20-25g of carbs. Not much, but still. I&amp;#8217;d lose weight faster without those carbs. I need to go buy healthy snaccks.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://emoprog.com/2014/02/01/entry</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://emoprog.com/2014/02/01/entry.html"/>
    <title>February 1, 2014</title>
    <published>2014-02-01T00:00:00-06:00</published>
    <updated>2014-02-01T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Louis Salin</name>
      <uri>http://emoprog.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Sleep: Long, but not continuous. I&amp;#8217;m still awefully sore from my abs workout two days ago. I kept waking up all night. 10:00pm to 8:30am&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Breakfast: two corn tortilla tacos with eggs, beans, chorizo, jalapenos&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Lunch: flank steak with kale&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Snacks: smoked salmon, coconut oil, cheese&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Dinner: sushi (2-3 pieces of a tempura fried one, used soy sauce), miso soup, 3 quail eggs, tuna, daikon radish, mayo of some sort&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Alcohol: two small glasses of sake&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was hungry all day! I&amp;#8217;m not sure why. Maybe it&amp;#8217;s because I need to recover from my workouts. Speaking of which&amp;#8230; I was so sore today! I still am. My hip flexors are preventing me from standing straight, but my abs are finally getting a bit better.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://emoprog.com/2014/01/31/entry</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://emoprog.com/2014/01/31/entry.html"/>
    <title>January 31, 2014</title>
    <published>2014-01-31T00:00:00-06:00</published>
    <updated>2014-01-31T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Louis Salin</name>
      <uri>http://emoprog.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Sleep: Horrible. Couldn&amp;#8217;t fall asleep until 11:45pm and woke up at 6:45am. Plus, I tossed and turned all night.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Breakfast: 3 eggs, cheese&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Lunch: none&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Snacks: none&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Dinner: 12 oz (ish) flank steak with a bunch of kale cooked with bacon and onions.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Alcohol: Tried a new cocktail with gin, Peychaud bitters and lemon bitters, orange juice. It was good. Then I had some whisky.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;D&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The power core workout I did last night turned my abs into jelly and prevented me from efficiently tossing and turning during the night, which added insult to injury. What a bad night. Last time I ate at Rudy&amp;#8217;s I had trouble sleeping that night as well. I need to keep that in mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I ate the way I want to eat in the future: just breakfast and dinner. I got a bit hungry, but I knew it wasn&amp;#8217;t real hunger and that I could easily last until dinder. This way, I don&amp;#8217;t have to waste an hour of work for lunch and I can come home earlier at night.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://emoprog.com/2014/01/30/entry</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://emoprog.com/2014/01/30/entry.html"/>
    <title>January 30, 2014</title>
    <published>2014-01-30T00:00:00-06:00</published>
    <updated>2014-01-30T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Louis Salin</name>
      <uri>http://emoprog.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Sleep: Woke up a lot during the night, otherwise sleep was good. 10:30pm to 9am.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Breakfast: I needed a big breakfast to last until diner time. 4 eggs, one potato hashbrown. I didn&amp;#8217;t even finish my plate.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Lunch: none&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Snacks: none&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Dinner: Ate diner at 9pm: Rudy&amp;#8217;s &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;BBQ&lt;/span&gt;. 1/2lb brisket, cole slaw, potato salad, water and NO bread.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Alcohol: none&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I ate breakfast and headed out to a college recruiting event from 11am to 6pm, after which I went rock climbing. I was there late enough to catch the power core class at 8pm and decided to give it a shot.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://emoprog.com/2014/01/29/entry</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://emoprog.com/2014/01/29/entry.html"/>
    <title>January 29, 2014</title>
    <published>2014-01-29T00:00:00-06:00</published>
    <updated>2014-01-29T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Louis Salin</name>
      <uri>http://emoprog.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Sleep: Short and alcohol induced. 1:30am to 9am.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Breakfast: a bowl of Cara&amp;#8217;s chili&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Lunch: a chicken salad, with balsamic vinaigrette and dried fruits and nuts&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Snacks: a few cashews&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Dinner: Tortilla chips, queso, pork in a salsa verde, a bit of rice&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Alcohol: a margarita and a shot of tequila&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I surprisingly felt good today, but fell apart at around 5pm. I think I&amp;#8217;m going to go back to working regular hours. Although I really liked working shorter days everyday, a few things bothered me. First, it&amp;#8217;s weird to come in late and leave early. I felt like I had to explain myself to my coworkers every day. Second, having to work on weekends is always a bummer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did like all the extra time I had, though. I read a lot more and worked longer on my project. Working full days will mean a lot less of that.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://emoprog.com/2014/01/28/entry</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://emoprog.com/2014/01/28/entry.html"/>
    <title>January 28, 2014</title>
    <published>2014-01-28T00:00:00-06:00</published>
    <updated>2014-01-28T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Louis Salin</name>
      <uri>http://emoprog.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Sleep: Good. 10:30pm to 7:45am.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Breakfast: 3 eggs, 2 pieces of bacon&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Lunch: a Frito pie with Cara&amp;#8217;s chili, which includes beans. So this was a bit more carb-y than what I usually eat, but it was delicious&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Snacks: walnuts&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Dinner: Chicken salad at Athenian! I can&amp;#8217;t help myself whenever I&amp;#8217;m downtown. Their salad is so good and fits my diet so well that it&amp;#8217;s all I ever eat.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Alcohol: A few. I went to a user group meeting and at a bar afterwards. I had 3 whiskey drinks (paid for by the user group sponsor) and one cocktail (paid for by a good friend of mine.) Sleep will suffer&amp;#8230;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I need to go to these user groups more often and get the pulse of the community. The only times I go is when I&amp;#8217;m looking for jobs or to see my friend Scott talk. I realized that the reason I stopped going was that I hardly learn anything new anymore, or nothing I can&amp;#8217;t learn from a blog post anyway. So I&amp;#8217;ve decided that I need to start teaching.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ll focus my area of teaching around the structure of software and start with the basic &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;SOLID&lt;/span&gt; principles.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  
 
</feed>
